[{"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c921", "question": "What is a group of Sparrows called?", "answer": "Host", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dcd", "question": "What British pop group did Bryan Ferry lead after Brian Eno's 1973 departure?", "answer": "Roxy Music", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339570", "question": "Who gets a visit from Santa Claus in, The Christmas That Almost Wasn't?", "answer": "Attorney Sam Whipple", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9b2", "question": "What team did Vince Lombardi coach to two Super Bowl victories?", "answer": "Green Bay Packers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede0d56ce05a3942286dbc", "question": "What was the name of the coffee shop in the TV series \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Central Perk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339014", "question": "In Egyptian mythology, who is the god of the underworld?", "answer": "Osiris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a767", "question": "In which US state is Gettysburg National Military Park?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf0b", "question": "How many tiles does a player play to score a bingo in Scrabble?", "answer": "7", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e75206d333868d34d73d", "question": "Which book in the Bible immediately follows the four gospels?", "answer": "Acts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ca3e1e44f0f6af5b066645", "question": "In mathematics which prefix refers to 10 to the power of minus 15?", "answer": "Femto", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c021", "question": "Which fashion designer was shot dead in the summer of 1997?", "answer": "Gianni Versace", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f7167a9e54d890926f6df", "question": "What is the family name of the ruling dynasty of Monaco?", "answer": "Grimaldi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a896", "question": "What city is home to the Milad Tower?", "answer": "Tehran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4a992661d1b4d384d5d697", "question": "What year did the TV show \"Gunsmoke\" change its length from 30 minutes to 1 hour?", "answer": "1961", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c7c49076251badbead5", "question": "Which newspaper incorrectly reported Thomas E. Dewey defeated Harry S. Truman in the 1948 U.S. Presidential Election?", "answer": "Chicago Daily Tribune -- Now known as Chicago Tribune, it had once referred to Truman as a \"nincompoop\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd9691d23c87fd04dd15e06", "question": "Christopher Jones was the captain of what famous ship?", "answer": "The Mayflower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b83e", "question": "What 2 articles of clothing are tokens in the standard Monopoly game?", "answer": "Shoe and Top Hat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfe2", "question": "What is the Latin word for poison?", "answer": "Virus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339337", "question": "How many children did Lucy and Desi have?", "answer": "Two", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a7", "question": "Guadalupe Mountains National Park is located in which US state?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cd72fe347d002c297e4bf", "question": "Which US state gets the most rainfall?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa5777c73aa70ea0b70b36", "question": "Which state features a motto that is a rough translation of its name?", "answer": "Texas (\"Tejas,\" means \"allies\" or \"friends.\" The motto of Texas, \"Friendship,\" is thus a loose translation of the state's name.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe528091bf59ab7d2e380fc", "question": "Before it was called the Big Mac, McDonald's signature sandwich went by what name?", "answer": "The Aristocrat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a19", "question": "What UK band had a #1 hit in 1981 with the song \"Don\u2019t You Want Me\"?", "answer": "Human League", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b468", "question": "What year did Ferdinand Porsche and his team started to design the VW Beetle?", "answer": "1934", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a46120565ad31a57c7bc", "question": "In which US state was the first Kentucky Fried Chicken franchise opened?", "answer": "Utah", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e6b502fb6c85e9e634ff45", "question": "Where is the \"Land of 10,000 Lakes\"?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb60d05dad637d903c882c", "question": "The Rungnado 1st of May Stadium, built in honor of the May Day holiday, exists in which country?", "answer": "North Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c90d01152800b05cac20f0c", "question": "In what city was Bruce Lee born in?", "answer": "San Francisco, California", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339741", "question": "Peter Marshall was the host of what game show for 15 years?", "answer": "The Hollywood Squares", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c60", "question": "What liqueur was Vincent Van Gogh said to be heavily drinking heavily the night he cut off his ear?", "answer": "Absinthe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4f7", "question": "What is better than stone in the paper, stone, scissors game?", "answer": "Paper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a1db20565ad31a57c7a8", "question": "Who popularized the white wedding dress?", "answer": "Queen Victoria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe937986bd93ce3a4e5f671", "question": "Dystychiphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Accidents", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c18d", "question": "What is the fourth letter of the Greek alphabet?", "answer": "Delta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb4f", "question": "\"Pips\" is the correct term for the dots on what game pieces?", "answer": "Dominoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ab", "question": "What mountain is the tallest point in Russia?", "answer": "Elbrus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339edb", "question": "What position was first held by Steve Allen?", "answer": "Tonight Show host", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ac", "question": "What popular film director/actor co-wrote the 1994 movie \"Natural Born Killers\"?", "answer": "Quentin Tarantino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bedf", "question": "Who won the US Open men's tennis title in 1990 at the age of just 19?", "answer": "Pete Sampras", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ce7", "question": "What Nobel Prize-winning author committed suicide by gunshot in 1961?", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339653", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what vehicle is described as \"A country-fried truck endorsed by a clown\"?", "answer": "Canyonero", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ea6", "question": "What screen legend made his final appearance in the movie \"Giant\"?", "answer": "James Dean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb10", "question": "What is the nickname given to the stretch between San Jose and San Francisco known for its many technology businesses?", "answer": "Silicon Valley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf4c", "question": "Which English club was formed as Ardwick FC?", "answer": "Manchester United", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c1", "question": "In Greek mythology who was the son of Hypnos, who is considered god of dreams?", "answer": "Morpheus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb40", "question": "What color is the 4-ball in a game of pool?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a46", "question": "What album was the first to be certified platinum by the RIAA?", "answer": "\"Their Greatest Hits\" by Eagles", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a1", "question": "After the Civil War, which Union general became the first president of the NRA?", "answer": "Ambrose Burnside", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea7e32ff048f679a45ac09", "question": "Automatonophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Human-like figures", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac53", "question": "What did woman use to redden their lips during the era of Louis XIV?", "answer": "Lemons", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a80a", "question": "What country controls the Mediterranean island of Corsica?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5937ea9308d98002fdd633a4", "question": "With what body part is otology involved?", "answer": "The Ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b467", "question": "What year did Ferdinand Porsche and his team finish the design of the VW Beetle?", "answer": "1938", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab55", "question": "What is the second largest country in South America?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ea", "question": "In which Star Wars movie does Darth Vader reveal that he is Luke Skywalker's father?", "answer": "The Empire Strikes Back", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b10e", "question": "During WWI, what disease caused 1/3 of all soldier's deaths?", "answer": "Spanish Flu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd81dced0de9af39e9d4693", "question": "What state elected a former pro wrestler as its governor?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7cf01877e98cb97778a49", "question": "Where is the \"Cathedral of Rum\"?", "answer": "Puerto Rico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b780", "question": "What city's Summer Olympics had the beaver Amik as their mascot?", "answer": "Montreal's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec26208dc25ca9e12ef647", "question": "Which country traditionally gives London's Trafalgar Square its Christmas tree?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec88caec223966ae8f8823", "question": "Which pop media icon was recently memorialized in \"World of Warcraft\" in late 2018?", "answer": "Stan Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ea0", "question": "Since 1961, where have Margo Magee, Tommie Thompson, and Lu Ann Powers lived?", "answer": "Apartment 3-G", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb64", "question": "What rank in the US Army is just above the rank of First Lieutenant?", "answer": "Captain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e38d2e1f6c8a670a7957c59", "question": "What is the maximum current of an LASCR (Light Activated Silicon Controlled Rectifier)?", "answer": "3 amps", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ef5", "question": "What 1984 Ratt hit featured a cross-dressing Milton Berle in its video?", "answer": "Round and Round", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a998", "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano \"Fuji\"?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592ead5df83302ff91e4647b", "question": "Sophophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Learning", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a513", "question": "In which sea is the island country of Malta?", "answer": "Mediterranean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339423", "question": "What basketball player starred alongside Jean Claude Van Damme in the movie \"Double Team\"?", "answer": "Dennis Rodman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e147934dd42e4a67cb8d3ed", "question": "Who painted the famous work of art known as \"The Death of Socrates\"?", "answer": "Jacques-Louis David", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae14", "question": "Montezuma was the emperor of which ancient society?", "answer": "Aztecs", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b0b", "question": "What is the last word of the Bible?", "answer": "Amen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a599", "question": "What old Massachusetts town is nicknamed \"Witch city\"?", "answer": "Salem", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac99", "question": "Which of the US Presidents was the first to be born in the 20th century?", "answer": "Lyndon B. Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a7f6096f5f79087132fb42", "question": "In finance, what does \"QRM\" stand for?", "answer": "Quantitative Risk Management", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b7abd426490a8cc1a6e529e", "question": "What is the capital city of England", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5a2", "question": "What makes popping corn pop?", "answer": "The water stored inside the kernel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5e", "question": "For what does the \"F.\" stand in the name F. Lee Bailey?", "answer": "Francis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e220fe83fe1f2a824b9c", "question": "What happened to the Soviet air force during the opening days of the German invasion?", "answer": "Up to 2000 aircraft were destroyed on the ground", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb0b", "question": "What protein is responsible for giving blood its color?", "answer": "Hemoglobin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339848", "question": "What comedian was nickname \"Mr. Television\"?", "answer": "Milton Berle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe73e36eec85e375820b272", "question": "In \"Adventures of Huckleberry Finn\", who is Huck's father?", "answer": "Pap", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad15", "question": "Who is the founder of Carthage?", "answer": "Dido", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133902f", "question": "Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman god Vulcan?", "answer": "Hephaestos", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a1a", "question": "What kind of creature is Mrs. Tiggy-Winkle in a book by Beatrix Potter?", "answer": "Hedgehog", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c622", "question": "What element is most commonly found in Earths atmosphere?", "answer": "Nitrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a7", "question": "Which country hosted the first Winter Olympic Games after World War II?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea3a9cff048f679a45ab2c", "question": "What color has the longest wavelength in the visible spectrum?", "answer": "Red", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4dd", "question": "What is the most mountainous country in Europe?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ff", "question": "What status did astronomers downgrade Pluto to in 2006?", "answer": "Dwarf Planet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae0", "question": "What small carrier attached to a motorcycle shares its name with a brandy cocktail?", "answer": "Sidecar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dbc", "question": "What holiday is celebrated with an aluminum pole, the Airing of Grievances, and Feats of Strength?", "answer": "Festivus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a37a", "question": "What is the capital of Portugal?", "answer": "Lisbon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac7b", "question": "Who became prime minister of Cuba in 1959?", "answer": "Fidel Castro", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0fc", "question": "Which word, taken from the French, translates literally as \"rotten pot\"?", "answer": "Potpourri", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6008ddb0f4f3bc4a292f8623", "question": "After World War II, who was the first leader of the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia?", "answer": "Ivan Ribar (From December 29. 2945 until January 14, 1953, he was the President of the Federal Assembly of Yugoslavia.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e7", "question": "Who is more commonly known as the Michelin Man?", "answer": "Bibendum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa15", "question": "What line on a map connects places of equal rainfall?", "answer": "Isohyet", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc1", "question": "What is divided by the Cassini Division?", "answer": "Saturn's rings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe73503eec85e375820b241", "question": "On two separate occasions, President Ford was shot at by which two people?", "answer": "Lynette \"Squeaky\" Fromme and Sara Jane Moore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3e9", "question": "What year did the Republic of South Sudan gain its independence?", "answer": "2011", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaad", "question": "Autodromo Nazionale Monza is located in which country?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015fad3fe83fe1f2a824c36", "question": "What was the profession of St. Patrick's father?", "answer": "St. Patrick's father was a deacon while his grandfather was a Christian priest.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600240884be4723ccac22166", "question": "In the film \"The Hunt for Red October,\" Captain Marko Ramius is from what country?", "answer": "Lithuania", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe767f1eec85e375820b29b", "question": "Which US state is named after a British island?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe93ac66bd93ce3a4e5f69b", "question": "What is the scientific study of animal biology?", "answer": "Zoology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a74", "question": "Matt Dillon and Kitty Russell were long-running characters on what TV series?", "answer": "Gunsmoke", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbdc36ce05a3942286ee1", "question": "What was the name of the bar Jerry Lundegaard went to in the film \"Fargo\"?", "answer": "King of Clubs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5aab2f4258d116dab4aecb48", "question": "What is racing driver's, Jean Alesi, birth name?", "answer": "Giovanni Alesi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa88473838c5c8a417f3e", "question": "What color is oxygen in liquid or solid form?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c79a", "question": "What year was the planet Neptune first discovered?", "answer": "1846", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f7", "question": "In the 1950s, the NFL experimented with what new color for their footballs?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ded0d5ea2747c8aff16d2d", "question": "Which country's wine might be labelled \"AOC\"?", "answer": "France's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe1f2e1145fb29466707397", "question": "What was the world's first digital quartz watch called?", "answer": "The Pulsar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ded2b7ea2747c8aff16d41", "question": "What was Eddie Money's career before becoming a musician?", "answer": "Police officer (trainee)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a06e", "question": "Who played Sandy in the made for TV adaptation of Grease Live?", "answer": "Julianne Hough", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab44", "question": "Vienna is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de7", "question": "What 1971 film was partially set in the Korova Milk Bar?", "answer": "A Clockwork Orange", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af3d", "question": "What did the Texan army shout during the Battle of San Jacinto?", "answer": "Remember the Alamo!", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a526", "question": "What are the five Great Lakes?", "answer": "Superior, Michigan, Huron, Erie and Ontario", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a83a", "question": "What US city's nicknames include \"The Crescent City\" and \"The City that Care Forgot\"?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a261", "question": "Which British group recorded the song \"The House of the Rising Sun\" in 1964?", "answer": "The Animals", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af6", "question": "What TV science guy wore a red polka-dot bow tie on the box of his \"Way Cool Game of Science\" CD-ROM?", "answer": "Bill Nye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb7fb7e83c707845b2132", "question": "The science of the origin and development of the universe is called what?", "answer": "Cosmology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff3c2eb4f032c0db195b487", "question": "What mathematician spent his life calculating the value of pi to 707 decimal places?", "answer": "William Shanks", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59008ddccf842fa4c4ba96ad", "question": "What is the state capital of Alaska?", "answer": "Juneau", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a048", "question": "In what year was the hit game \"Minecraft\" released?", "answer": "2009", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c9f7b1b4e2c7fbd389674b", "question": "How is a Long black coffee different from an Americano?", "answer": "The espresso is poured on top of the hot water, instead of before", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e147ef76ca6dac04a20ca52", "question": "Who was the first woman to fly solo across the Atlantic Ocean?", "answer": "Amelia Earhart", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe0e52cfcbed638185eaa2b", "question": "The Yalu River separates China from which country?", "answer": "North Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6d7", "question": "What professor of physics oversaw the design and assembly of the first atomic bomb?", "answer": "J. Robert Oppenheimer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e64406d333868d34d730", "question": "How many aircraft carriers did Japan lose in World War II?", "answer": "26", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597cda00e347d002c297e4d1", "question": "Who was James Stewart's female co-start in Hitchcock's \"Rear Window\"?", "answer": "Grace Kelly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b90e", "question": "What 2 letters are often used as a written abbreviation for \"hugs and kisses\"?", "answer": "XO", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60173d2b44491cbd7c5a17aa", "question": "What is the oldest active international airline?", "answer": "KLM Royal Dutch Airlines -- Founded in 1919, KLM is also the\u00a0oldest airline in the world\u00a0still operating under its original name.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe698a120565ad31a57c736", "question": "Who was Telemachus?", "answer": "Odysseus' son", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a876", "question": "In what city would you find \"Peachtree Street\"?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c512", "question": "What is the largest muscle in the human body?", "answer": "Gluteus maximus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a06d", "question": "What artist had the first rap album to ever go to No. 1 on the US pop charts?", "answer": "MC Hammer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd16", "question": "What term is used for surfers and skaters who prefer to have their left foot on the back of the board?", "answer": "Goofy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b33a", "question": "On what date did America become an independent nation?", "answer": "July 4th, 1776", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec7", "question": "Which British Sailor and Explorer was killed by Hawaiian natives in 1779?", "answer": "James Cook", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baae", "question": "What company helped the US Army Corps of Engineers develop the \"walkie-talkie\" in the early 1930\u2019s?", "answer": "Motorola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60078250bd51d85e222ab656", "question": "What did Claude Monet's father want him to be?", "answer": "Grocer (Monet's father disapproved of his painting. He wanted him to go into the family\u00a0grocery business.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6f8", "question": "Which state is home to the Fort Apache Indian Reservation?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5941257abab1e6f9796f1b54", "question": "Which character is always trying to steal the secret Krusty Krab Recipe on \"SpongeBob SquarePants\"?", "answer": "Plankton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae95e6574a5ce6b56b825b", "question": "What is Beethoven's sixth symphony known as?", "answer": "The Pastoral Symphony", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c90d", "question": "What is the young offspring of the Antelope called?", "answer": "Calf", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60173e6544491cbd7c5a17b0", "question": "The Wright brothers originally ran what kind of business?", "answer": "Bicycle repair and design -- The name of their business was Wright Cycle Company.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c840", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the islets of Langerhans?", "answer": "The pancreas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58be2cd28faf425cf37add78", "question": "What year was actor Mel Gibson born?", "answer": "1956", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c0", "question": "From 1948 to 1950, the Fender Telecaster was known by what alternate name?", "answer": "Broadcaster", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133907f", "question": "Who wrote a book about John Harrison, entitled \"Longitude\"?", "answer": "Dava Sobel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133939c", "question": "Who plays the role of Captain John Miller in the movie \"Saving Private Ryan\"?", "answer": "Tom Hanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4de0906d333868d34d70d", "question": "Which battle was fought on August 22, 1485?", "answer": "Battle Of Bosworth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca3e", "question": "Which element appears tenth on the periodic table?", "answer": "Neon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60173fea44491cbd7c5a17b8", "question": "The Battle of Austerlitz took place during which war?", "answer": "Napoleonic Wars", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c79", "question": "What 7th century Homerian epic tells the story of the Trojan War?", "answer": "The Iliad", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601371c0138175489539638d", "question": "Which musician wrote the theme song for Johnny Carson's \"The Tonight Show\"?", "answer": "Paul Anka -- The song earned him massive royalties. According to Anka, he received $200 every time the song was played.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "593c4b5db8198b9a2b077963", "question": "The film \"Casablanca\" takes place during which war?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aff7", "question": "What New York building, completed in 1931, was at the time the world's tallest?", "answer": "Empire State Building", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4e7", "question": "How many colored squares are there on a Rubik's Cube?", "answer": "54", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f89", "question": "Who is the author of the book \"The Life-changing Magic of Tidying Up\"?", "answer": "Marie Kondo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e6bc59fb6c85e9e634ff5c", "question": "Who sang \"All I Wanna Do\"?", "answer": "Sheryl Crow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf77", "question": "What is the fear of the number 8 known as?", "answer": "Octophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133926d", "question": "Which rap star was born Cordozar Calvin Broadus, Jr.?", "answer": "Snoop Dogg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febad567e83c707845b20f1", "question": "What is the softest metal at room temperature?", "answer": "Caesium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133951c", "question": "Who was the second actor in history to decline an Oscar?", "answer": "Marlon Brando", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e5f10d3d274615ecf514537", "question": "What is another name for the \"Battle of Greasy Grass\"?", "answer": "The Battle of the Little Bighorn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a71c", "question": "Which US state shares a border with Ohio, Indiana and Wisconsin?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede2266ce05a3942286dcd", "question": "\"Santa Baby\" contributed to which singer\u2019s fame?", "answer": "Eartha Kitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b65a", "question": "Hall of Fame running back Jim Brown played his entire pro career for which NFL team?", "answer": "Cleveland Browns", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d36", "question": "Anne Hathaway was married to what famous English poet?", "answer": "William Shakespeare", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdab55f0b8cce1e6fda704c", "question": "Caff\u00e8 corretto is espresso \"corrected\" with what substance?", "answer": "Alcohol", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba8", "question": "What 1975 Oscar-winning film features the sadistic Nurse Ratched?", "answer": "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a4", "question": "What city is the TV show \"Sex and the City\" based in?", "answer": "New York", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa5886ce05a3942286ec2", "question": "What classic music was used in the television series \"The Lone Ranger\"?", "answer": "March of the Swiss Soldiers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a70d", "question": "Which US state is home to the Hopi Indian Reservation?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a358", "question": "What South American city does an 82 foot statue of Christ overlook?", "answer": "Rio de Janeiro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399bd", "question": "What duo\u2019s first names were Don and Phil?", "answer": "The Everly Brothers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd6", "question": "What band was the only rap band to perform at Live Aid in 1985?", "answer": "Run D.M.C.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a3b", "question": "What was the occupation of James Woods' character on the TV show \"Shark\"?", "answer": "Lawyer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5f6c6ce05a3942286e42", "question": "Where is Paddington Bear from?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339360", "question": "What \"Smokey and the Bandit\" movie star played the blacksmith on \"Gunsmoke\"?", "answer": "Burt Reynolds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c371", "question": "What is the common name for the main vent at the top of a volcano?", "answer": "Crater", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba8", "question": "Which US state has Cheyenne as its capital city?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ab99adb21a8909e5c332d25", "question": "What is the Kelvin scale used to measure?", "answer": "Temperature", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b5c901dd7bf43be5e7d5", "question": "What sporting event is referred to as \"The Run for the Roses\"?", "answer": "Kentucky Derby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c30a", "question": "What is the Fahrenheit equivalent of -40 degrees Celsius", "answer": "-40 degrees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e23", "question": "Who's the most famous resident of Mr. Peebles' pet shop?", "answer": "Magilla Gorilla", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8f3", "question": "What range contains the world's highest mountains not located in Asia?", "answer": "The Andes", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5937eed608d98002fdd633d9", "question": "From which musical did \"One Night in Bangkok Makes a Hard Man Humble\" and \"I Know Him So Well\" come?", "answer": "Chess", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396f7", "question": "What were Moe Howard, Larry Fine and Curly Howard better known as?", "answer": "The 3 Stooges", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078c190eee65b76b9f266f", "question": "America stayed neutral in World War I until Germany threatened what?", "answer": "Commercial shipping (In March 1917, four U.S. commercial ships were sunk by Germany, and the U.S. declared war in April 1917.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133935b", "question": "Who played the role of Sue Ann Nivens on \"The Mary Tyler Moore Show\"?", "answer": "Betty White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a421", "question": "What is the world's highest waterfall?", "answer": "Angel Falls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3f6", "question": "If \"feline\" is used to describe cat-like, what word describes bear-like?", "answer": "Ursine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339681", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Homer's middle name?", "answer": "Jay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59774255284458f1d785441f", "question": "Who played Secret Service Agent James West in The 1966-1968 television series \"The Wild, Wild, West\"?", "answer": "Robert Conrad", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a671", "question": "What capital city is located on the shores of Chesapeake Bay?", "answer": "Annapolis", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f10", "question": "Whose military textbook \"Infantry Attacks\" was read, famously by George Patton?", "answer": "Erwin Rommel's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a221", "question": "Who played Beau Geste in the 1939 film by the same name?", "answer": "Gary Cooper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7b1", "question": "In what lunar phase is the moon when it is three-quarters full?", "answer": "Gibbous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefbed06ce05a3942286ef7", "question": "Who first recorded the song \"Venus\"?", "answer": "Shocking Blue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd665bca5bfecdd737e0862", "question": "How long ago did mammoths go extinct?", "answer": "4000 years ago", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921f", "question": "What is the collective name for Italian-made western movies?", "answer": "Spaghetti westerns", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5921fd34a4edfd43a087adc8", "question": "Which team do England play in The Ashes cricket competition?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b00a", "question": "What region was explored by Juan Rodriguez Cabrillo?", "answer": "California", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a8", "question": "Who wrote the novel 1984?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7d3", "question": "What popular breed of pet rabbit was named for the Asian capital where it was first domesticated?", "answer": "Angora", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7bb", "question": "The Linux operating system was created by which software engineer?", "answer": "Linus Torvalds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acab", "question": "What month in 1912 saw the Titanic go down?", "answer": "April", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59029d79cad1ec93f27df74e", "question": "In the beer world, what does the abbreviation F.G. stand for?", "answer": "Final Gravity", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae00", "question": "Who took 18 days to write the Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d11a2a4fea7fe947a22294", "question": "\"The Diary of a Young Girl\" is also known under what title?", "answer": "The Diary of Anne Frank", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339212", "question": "What rock star is credited as a co-writer and backing singer for David Bowie's \"Fame\"?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd6997e83c707845b216a", "question": "What was Forrest Gump's favorite pastime?", "answer": "Running", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133982a", "question": "What type of music did Benny Goodman play?", "answer": "Jazz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfcd", "question": "In bowling what is the term for knocking down all pins with 2 consecutive balls?", "answer": "A Spare\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dffa59616e6c6d4eba4ff", "question": "Which US Holiday is celebrated on October 12th?", "answer": "Columbus Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cadc", "question": "What is the offspring of a male horse and a female donkey?", "answer": "A Hinny", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a343", "question": "The 2002 US film \"The Ring\" is based on a 1990's film produced and released in what other country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397de", "question": "Which actor had to swim for his life whilst filming The Beach in 1999?", "answer": "Leonardo Di Caprio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbf0b6ce05a3942286efa", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Material Girl\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5e016ce05a3942286e2e", "question": "Which high school movie\u2019s tagline is \"One man's struggle to take it easy\"?", "answer": "\"Ferris Bueller's Day Off\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8b73ec223966ae8f883e", "question": "The Grateful Dead's highly-devoted fanbase are known as what?", "answer": "Deadheads", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a616", "question": "Where is the Trafalgar Cemetery located?", "answer": "Gibraltar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b71", "question": "What comic strip did Scott Adams create while working for Pacific Bell?", "answer": "Dilbert", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba64", "question": "Which US city is home to the Second City Comedy Troupe?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c0a", "question": "What cartoon was created by Gary Larson?", "answer": "The Far Side", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abf3", "question": "What major city lies on the River Torrens?", "answer": "Adelaide", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe76f54eec85e375820b2e7", "question": "Where can you find the iconic Apollo Theater?", "answer": "Harlem, New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b021", "question": "Who was U.S. President when electricity was installed in the White House, in 1891?", "answer": "Benjamin Harrison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ed", "question": "Which more successful group did Mick Abrahams leave in 1969 to form Blodwyn Pig?", "answer": "Jethro Tull", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b46e", "question": "Which politician is known as Tarzan?", "answer": "Michael Heseltine\u00a0", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbd7", "question": "What South American country was a former member of OPEC?", "answer": "Ecuador", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c778", "question": "What animal species were depicted as evil characters in \"The Wonderful Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "Monkeys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a48f", "question": "On the bank of which river does the Portuguese capital of Lisbon stand?", "answer": "The Tagus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6e6", "question": "Who won the light heavyweight boxing medal at the 1960 Rome Olympics?", "answer": "Cassius Clay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ef", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows\" what does the acronym RAB stand for?", "answer": "Regulus A. Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a08c", "question": "What band released the hit song \"Radio Gaga\"?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339497", "question": "How many children do Daniel and Miranda have in the movie \"Mrs. Doubtfire\"?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f97", "question": "What were the dolls in the novel \"Valley of the Dolls\"?", "answer": "Pills", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133889a", "question": "Where did Gulliver find a race of tiny people?", "answer": "Lilliput", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "592eb109f83302ff91e464a3", "question": "What company makes the Larry O'Brien Trophy?", "answer": "Tiffany & Co.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b524", "question": "What is Prosciutto?", "answer": "Italian dry-cured ham", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf84", "question": "What is British politician William Hague's middle name?", "answer": "Jefferson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133968f", "question": "Who played the Black Knight in the 1975 movie \"Monty Python and the Holy Grail\"?", "answer": "John Cleese", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe93d046bd93ce3a4e5f6ae", "question": "Who invented the telescope?", "answer": "Hans Lipperhey (or Lippershey)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339675", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what color is the tablecloth in the Simpsons' kitchen?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae927e574a5ce6b56b822e", "question": "What type of lettuce should be used in a classic Caesar Salad?", "answer": "Romaine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d0442596a59cbdfbd379", "question": "Who said, \"When I do good, I feel good. When I do bad, I feel bad. That's my religion\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b3233d5bf195a31e15d739f", "question": "What product changed its original name in the US from the \"Soundabout\"?", "answer": "Sony's Walkman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cab", "question": "In Greek mythology, the hundred-eyed Argus was honored by Hera by being transformed into what bird?", "answer": "Peacock", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5904a106cf93664eb10486bc", "question": "The \"Bodansky Unit\", now an obsolete unit, used to measure the concentration of what in the blood stream?", "answer": "Alkaline phosphatase", "category": "science"}]